Esta lição dez de Pimsleur inglês um. Listen to this
English conversation. Escute esta conversa em inglês.
Listen to this English conversation.
John, would you like to have something to eat with me?
Yes, I would. But at what time? At two o'clock?
No, later. Much later. Oh, I understand.
At eight o'clock or at nine o'clock? Yes, at eight o'clock.
Okay, eight o'clock. Goodbye, Mary. Nesta conversa,
você ouviu much later, o que quer dizer muito mais
tarde. Listen again. Escute outra vez. Listen again.
John, would you like to have something to eat with me?
Yes, I would. But at what time? At two o'clock?
No, later. Much later. Oh, I understand.
At eight o'clock or at nine o'clock? Yes,
at eight o'clock. Okay, eight o'clock. Goodbye,
Mary. Você se lembra de como se diz eu
gostaria de comer algo?
I'd like something to eat.
Diga, eu gostaria de almoçar.
I'd like to have lunch.
Pergunte, o que você gostaria de fazer?
What would you like to do?
To do. Usando tomar,
tente dizer: Eu também gostaria de comer algo.
I'd like to have something to eat too.
Pergunte: Com quem?
With whom?
Com você. With you.
Usando tomar, diga: Eu gostaria de comer algo com você.
I'd like to have something to eat with you.
Diga está bem. Okay.
Agora pergunte o que você quer fazer.
What do you want to do?
Diga eu quero comprar algo.
I want to buy something.
To buy. I want
to buy something.
Agora diga-me que você gostaria de comprar algo.
I'd like to buy something.
Eu gostaria de comprar duas cervejas.
I'd like to buy two beers.
Two beers.
Pergunte: a que horas?
At what time?
Jīgē àomè.
At 1 o'clock.
O'clock.
One. One.
One o'clock.
At 1 o'clock.
At one o'clock.
Pergunte às nove, está bem?
At nine o'clock, okay?
Responda não. Às nove não.
No, not at nine o'clock.
Not at nine o'clock.
Às oito.
At eight
o'clock.
Eight.
Eight. At eight o'clock.
At eight o'clock. Chica está
bem às duas.
Okay, at two o'clock.
Two.
Two. Okay, at two o'clock.
Diga não, você não entende.
No, you don't understand.
Pergunte-lhe se ela gostaria de beber algo.
Would you
like something to drink?
Responda: Não, eu agradeço, mas eu gostaria de comer algo.
No, thank you, but I'd like something to eat.
Diga sinto muito, eu não entendo.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
Pergunte o que você gostaria de fazer?
What would you like to do?
To do.
Usando tomar, diga: Você gostaria de beber algo?
Would you like to have something to drink?
E diga: Ou você gostaria de comer algo?
Or would you like to have something to eat?
Diga eu não sei.
I don't know.
Usando tomar, diga eu gostaria de comer algo.
I'd like to have something to eat.
Pergunte com quem?
With whom?
Pergunte comigo?
With me?
With me? Diga sim,
um restaurante.
Yes, at a restaurant.
Sim, no restaurante Avenida Parque.
Yes, at the Park Avenue Restaurant.
Pergunte: Você sabe?
Do you know?
Você sabe onde fica o restaurante? Preste atenção na
ordem das palavras.
Do you know where the restaurant is?
Where the restaurant is?
Agora pergunte: Onde fica o restaurante?
Where is the restaurant?
Pergunte outra vez. Você sabe onde fica o restaurante?
Do you know where the restaurant is?
Pergunte. Fica aqui?
Is it here?
Responda-lhe: Não, não fica aqui.
No, it's not here.
Diga: Fica lá.
It's over there.
Pergunte: a que horas?
At what time?
Agora, é assim que se pergunta que horas são.
Escute e repita: What time is it?
Is it? Is it?
What time is it?
Pergunte-me que horas são.
É assim que se diz são nove ou são nove horas.
Escute e repita. It's nine o'clock.
It's it's nine o'clock.
Pergunte-me outra vez que horas são.
What time is it?
Responda são duas horas.
It's two o'clock.
It's two o'clock. É assim que se diz são cinco horas. Escute e repita.
It's five o'clock.
Five.
Five. It's five
o'clock.
Diga-me, são cinco horas.
It's five o'clock.
Pergunte-me outra vez que horas são.
What time is it?
Escute e repita a resposta: são três horas.
It's three o'clock. Three.
Three. It's three o'clock.
It's three o'clock.
Diga-me, são três horas?
Three. Agora diga-me que são cinco horas.
It's five o'clock.
Escute e repita: são quatro horas.
It's four o'clock.
Four.
Four. It's four o'clock.
It's four o'clock.
Diga-me, são quatro horas?
Diga-me que são cinco horas.
It's five o'clock. Diga-me que são duas horas.
It's two o'clock.
Two. It's two o'clock.
Diga-me
que são quatro horas.
It's four o'clock.
Four. It's four
Tente perguntar se são quatro horas.
Is it four o'clock? Is it
four o'clock?
Pergunte-me se são duas horas.
Is it two o'clock?
Diga não, são três horas.
No, it's three o'clock.
Diga-me, são oito horas.
It's eight o'clock.
Diga quatro horas.
Four o'clock.
Pergunte que horas são.
What time is it?
Diga cinco horas.
Five o'clock.
Nove horas.
Nine o'clock.
Três horas.
Three o'clock.
Cinco horas.
Five o'clock.
Quatro horas.
Four o'clock.
Pergunte-me que horas são.
What time is it?
What time is it, please?
Diga, eu não sei, mas eu gostaria de comer algo.
I don't know, but I'd like something to eat.
Diga agora não, mais tarde.
Not now, later.
Não, eu vou comer agora. Escute e repita.
No, I'm going to eat now.
Going. Going to.
Going to eat.
I'm going to eat.
I'm going to eat now.
Diga-me que você vai comer agora.
Tente dizer você vai.
You're going.
Going.
Tente dizer
você vai comer.
You're going to eat.
Going to eat.
Agora inverta a ordem das palavras para perguntar: Você vai
comer? Are you going to
eat?
Are you?
Are you going to eat?
Tente dizer: Sim, eu vou almoçar.
Yes, I'm going to have lunch.
Agora.
Now. Diga eu vou almoçar agora.
I'm going to have lunch now.
Diga, eu vou comer.
I'm going to eat.
À cinco.
At five o'clock.
Eu vou comer às cinco.
I'm going to eat at five o'clock.
Agora pergunte-me se eu vou comer às cinco.
Are you going to eat at five o'clock?
Responda: Não, às oito.
No at eight o'clock.
Usando tomar, tente dizer: Mas eu vou beber algo.
But I'm going to have something to drink.
Está bem? Okay.
Pergunte quando.
When? When?
Diga às três ou às quatro.
At three o'clock or at four o'clock.
Usando tomar, diga eu vou beber algo às nove.
I'm going to have something to drink at nine o'clock.
Pergunte: Que horas são agora?
What time is it now?
Tente dizer é uma hora agora.
It's one o'clock now.
One o'clock.
Agora diga eu agradeço. Eu vou almoçar.
Thank you. I'm going to have lunch.
E eu gostaria de duas cervejas.
And I'd like two beers.
Agora, a moça vai conversar com você. Responda.
Hello.
Hello. How are
you?
Fine, thanks. I'm fine,
thank you.
Would you like to have lunch with me?
Yes, thanks. Yes,
I would.
Ela vai propor vários horários. Cada vez que ela sugerir uma
hora, você não concordará e você vai propor continuamente comer
uma hora mais tarde. At what time would you like to
eat? At 8 o'clock?
No, at 9 o'clock.
No, not at 9 o'clock. At 2 o'clock, okay?
No, at 3 o'clock.
No, not at 2 o'clock. At 3 o'clock.
3 o'clock? No thanks, but at 4 o'clock,
okay?
No, at 5 o'clock.
No, not at 4 o'clock. At 5 o'clock.
No, not at five o'clock. Pergunte-lhe quando
ela gostaria de almoçar.
When would you like to have lunch?
I don't know. Pergunte-lhe se ela quer almoçar.
Do you want to have lunch?
Yes, but when? Diga-lhe que você vai almoçar agora.
I'm going to have lunch now.
Pergunte-lhe se ela vai almoçar com você.
Are you going to have lunch with me?
Como ela te diz, sim, eu vou almoçar com você.
Yes, I'm going to have lunch with you.
Pergunte-lhe, mas quando?
But when?
Later, much later. A partir de agora,
todas as lições têm uma leitura complementar.